you get up in the morning you could have
work you come over you have you see you
watch telly a bit you could have bed you
get up and you're gonna work I mean look
at it other ways of living life than
this drudgery this world is crazy
because it's so limited the way it is
the way it's structured its slavery it's
not serving people people are serving it
that's what we are we're slaves to a
system politicians are slaves to a
system they go into the system they
didn't going to change it the system
changes then
[Applause]
and what we do is we put the child into
the corridor of this grade system for
the kind of come on kitty kitty kitty
and yeah you're going to kill a guard
that's the great danger cause when you
finish that you'll get into first grade
and then calm first lady for second
grade so on and then you get out of
great students of high school and it's
revving up the thing is coming then
you're going to go to college by
children you get into graduate school
and when you're through with graduate
school you go out to join the world then
you get into some racket where you're
selling insurance and they've got that
quantity and you're going to make that
and all the time this thing is coming
it's coming it's coming that great thing
of the success you're working then when
you wake up one day about 40 years old
you say my god have arrived I'm there
and you don't feel very different from
what you always sell and there's a
slight letdown because you feel as a
hood and the water hose the dreadful
hooks they made you miss everything we
thought our life by analogy with a
journey with a pilgrimage which had a
serious purpose at the end the thing was
to get to that end success or whatever
it is or maybe heaven after you're dead
but we missed the point the whole way
along it was a musical thing you were
supposed sink or down while a new leader
displayed
and the world impoverishes itself by
spending a trillion dollars a year on
preparations for war and by employing
perhaps half the scientists and high
technologists on the planet in military
endeavours how would we explain all this
to a dispassionate extraterrestrial
observer what account would we give of
our stewardship of the planet Earth we
have heard the rationales offered by the
superpowers we know who speaks for the
nation's but who speaks for the human
species who speaks for Earth from an
extraterrestrial perspective our global
civilization is clearly on the edge of
failure in the most important task it
faces preserving the lives and
well-being of its citizens and the
future habitability of the planet but if
we're willing to live with the growing
likelihood of nuclear war shouldn't we
also be willing to explore vigorously
every possible means to prevent a
nuclear war shouldn't we consider in
every nation major changes in the
traditional ways of doing things a
fundamental restructuring of economic
political social and religious
institutions we reached a point where
there can be no more special interests
or special cases nuclear arms threatened
every person on the earth fundamental
changes in society sometimes labeled
impractical or contrary to human nature
as if nuclear war were practical as if
there were only one human nature but
fundamental changes can clearly be made
were surrounded by them in the last two
centuries abject slavery which was with
us for thousands of years has almost
entirely been eliminated in a
stirring worldwide revolution women
systematically mistreated for millennia
are gradually gaining the political and
economic power traditionally denied and
some wars of aggression have recently
been stopped curtailed because of a
revulsion felt by the people in the
aggressor Nations the old appeals to
racial sexual religious chauvinism and
to rabid nationalist fervor are
beginning not to work
a new consciousness is developing which
sees the earth as a single organism and
recognizes that an organism at war with
itself is doomed we are one planet
[Music]
the human could be realized that we are
all one basically not as an idea but as
a fact because when you go to live here
you see the miserable little shushing
the anxiety the despair of people
running to their petty little gods whom
they have created if you come to Europe
it's exactly the same thing if your
sensor first to realize not verbally but
in your heart you're glad Oh
that human beings right through the wall
go through the same agony that one goes
through the loneliness the despair the
depression the extraordinary uncertainty
insecurity the very ten thousand mile
zero 200 for fear they are all
psychologically bound together if one
realizes that for solving your battery
of blood oh you know honey and you're
responsible
don't you see you're very proud before I
go even though this is the world where
good manner murdered men try and help or
murder and cut down in the prime of your
youth and hacks and mediocre infectious
run everything else I'm going to share
with you a vision that I had because I
loved you and you feel it
we know that money spent on nuclear
weapons and defense every year trillions
of dollars correct and said and said
that's great exist and we spend that
money feeding and clothing the poor of
the world and it would pay for it many
times over not one human being excluded
we could as one race explore outer space
together in peace forever I think our
society is run by insane people for
insane objects and objectives and I
think that's what I saw when I was 16
and 12 way down the line but I expressed
it differently all through my life it's
the same thing I'm expressing older but
now I can put into that sentence I think
were being run by maniacs for maniac who
means end if anybody can put on paper
what our government and the American
government etc and the Russian China
what they are actually trying to do you
know on how what they think they're
doing I'd be very pleased to know what
they think they're doing I think they're
all insane you know but I'm liable to be
put away as insane for expressing them
you know that's what's insane of them
you know what would change the world
overnight is if we as a human race
started doing what we knew to be right
and just in the circumstances that we
face instead of making those decisions
as so many people do and have long done
on basis of what is right for me me me
in this circumstance that I face ok the
just thing to do might not be in the
moment the best thing to do but it's the
just and right thing to do and if we
started doing what we knew to be right
when we faced with these decisions as
opposed to what we perceive is right for
us in the moment although doing what is
right is right for us in the eternity
then everything would change
[Music]
if we want a world peace then be
peaceful it sounds trite it sounds
simple but it's devastatingly profound
that's what we need to be with each
other you know we have people going on
anti-war marches who are hurling abuse
at each other in their relationships and
stuff like that if we war with each
other then the collective version of
that is warring collectively we want
peace let's be peaceful we want a world
of kindness and let's be kind and it
must come for goodness sake it must if
we're all kind to each other we live in
a kind world Martin Luther King said
cowardice ask the question is it safe
experience he asked the question is in
politic fantasy ask the question is it
popular but conscience ask the question
is it right there comes a time when one
must take a position that is neither
safe nor partic nor popular but one must
take it because it is right and we
enough of us take that stance everything
changes the revolution is not a
revolution of weapons it's not a
revolution of fighting it's not a
revolution of hatred it's a revolution
of perception because everything changes
ah I am a lion then I'm not the lamb I
kept seeing in the mirror and the world
kept telling me I was and then that
spreaded itself out into the true nature
of who we are
here's to the crazy ones The Misfits the
rebels troublemakers the round pegs in
the square holes ones receiving
difference they're not fond of rules and
they have no respect the status quo you
can quote them disagree with them
glorify or vilify them now the only
thing you can't do is ignore them
because they change race forward and
while some may see them as the crazy
ones we see genius
is the people who are crazy enough to
think they can change the world not ones
who do
you